♪ In the not too distant future ♪
♪ Next Sunday AD ♪
♪ There was a guy named Joel ♪
♪ Not too different than you or me ♪
♪ He worked in a satellite loading bay ♪
♪ Just polishing switches to pay his way ♪
♪ He did his job with
the a cheerful face ♪
♪ But his bosses didn't like him ♪
♪ So they shot him into space ♪
♪ With seven cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst ever made ♪
♪ Joel says when you got lemons ♪
♪ You make lemonade ♪
♪ Now keep in mind he can't control ♪
♪ When the movies begin or end ♪
♪ Because he used the extra parts ♪
♪ To make his robot friends ♪
♪ Robot roll call Cambot ♪
♪ Servo ♪
♪ Gypsy ♪
♪ Crow ♪
♪ If you're wondering how
he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science facts ♪
♪ Just repeat to yourself
it's just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax ♪
♪ For Mystery Science Theater 3000 ♪
(vault banging)
- Hey, hi, everybody,
my name is Joel Hodgson,
this is Crow
and sorry we're on the satellite of love.
We're marooned in outer space.
Cambot you can bring it in a little bit
and it's frustration
'cause it's Thanksgiving.
You know, at least we got to see
the Macy's Thanksgiving
Day Parade, you know.
- Yes, I noticed they're still using
that Underdog balloon.
Say, does he get residuals for that?
- No, Crow, Underdog
is a cartoon character.
Nobody gets residuals
for being an overinflated caricature
filled with hot air.
- What about Geraldo?
- Now that's funny.
- It is?
- Yeah.
(Crow laughing)
- Oh, we got movie sign.
Today's movie is "Revenge
of the Mysterons from Mars."
It's filmed in super marionation.
You go through, we gotta go around.
Let's cheese it, Crow.
(vault creaking)
(grand music)
(suspenseful music)
- [Mysteron] This is a
priority planned mission
to Mysteron Imperial Council.
We have followed standard procedure
in sending our message of good will
to the inhabitants of this system,
but they ruthlessly
and without provocation
have attacked our base.
In retaliation for the violent action,
we are launching an attack
that will result in total destruction
of the third planet known as Earth.
(logo hissing)
(suspenseful music)
(gentle music)
(upbeat music)
- [Man] First picture transmission starts
in 35 seconds.
30 seconds.
- They must have spotted it.
What's the flight profile look like?
- It looks like this.
- Right on target.
21,000 miles from Mars.
- [Joel] Hey, Crow.
- [Man] 20 seconds.
10 seconds.
Nine.
- [Joel] See what's gonna happen.
(explosion pounding)
- One, zero.
Start transmission countdown.
(counter clicking)
- Have we done it?
- We know know for nearly four minutes.
Mars is about 43 million miles away.
It'll take that long for
the signals to reach us.
- That is if the Mysterons haven't
already destroyed the satellite.
- I'll report to cloud base.
- Right.
(suspenseful music)
- [Joel] Cloud base.
- What's the latest
situation, Captain Blue?
- We're at K14 observatory.
The satellite should have
started transmitting.
We're waiting for the first pictures.
- Thank you, Captain Blue.
Keep me informed.
- SIG, Colonel.
How do you rate our
chances, Captain Scarlet?
- Well, it's hard to
deceive the Mysterons,
but there's always a chance.
(counter clicking)
- Signal to noise ratio 0124
DB, definition positive.
- Good.
Check video.
- Video check positive.
Beam width and flex density AOI.
- Check all primary circuits.
- Computer feed out,
primary circuits, positive.
(counter clicking)
- Well, we'll so now know.
Check video.
- I just did.
- [Man] Well, do it again.
- It's getting pretty tense.
- Yes, a lot of time and effort
has gone into this project.
No one's had much sleep
these last three days.
- [Joel] Oh, I am.
- [Crow] Now we can
sleep through the movie.
- Signal's still strong.
It's not being jammed.
(machine beeping)
(counter clicking)
- [Joel] They got a satellite dish
like you wouldn't believe.
- [Crow] It's only a model.
- [Joel] Somebody just made a pod.
- Close ups of Mars.
43 million miles across
space to that screen.
- 20 seconds.
Stand by.
Start video recording 15 seconds, now.
- Here they come.
- [Man] Five, four, three, two.
- We've lost the signal.
- Check it.
- No possible doubt.
It's been destroyed two seconds
before the first picture transmission.
- The Mysterons have
destroyed the satellite.
Phase one complete according to planned.
- [Mysterons] This is the
voice of the Mysterons.
We know that you can hear us earth men.
The eye that dares to look upon our planet
has been destroyed.
You will never succeed.
You will never discover the
secret of the Mysterons.
We will be avenged.
- [Joel] Feels like
we're really here, Crow.
- [Crow] Wow, it does, ooh.
- Urbinol internal circuits, Leftenant?
- Yes, sir.
- Members of Spectrum,
as you have heard the
first satellite launched
to orbit Mars and
relayed pictures to earth
has been destroyed by the Mysterons.
This was, of course, anticipated
and the operation will
continue as planned.
- [Joel] I wonder why they
destroyed the pictures?
- SK14 observatory is at present beyond
the range of the Angel aircraft.
- [Crow] You say something?
- Our base will travel immediately
to a position 50 miles
west of the observatory
in the Himalayas.
From there we will maintain
aerial surveillance.
For the next 24 hours,
all Spectrum personnel
are on red alert.
This exercise is part of a
larger plan, Operation Sword
and we must succeed, that is all.
Leftenant Green?
- Yes, sir?
- [Colonel White] Start horizontal jets.
(triumphant music)
- Well, looks like we're underway.
- Maximum safe cruise, Colonel.
- [Joel] Look at the Jacuzzi he's got.
- Set a course 142 magnetic.
And maintain present speed.
Phase two has begun.
(grand music)
- [Joel] Looks like Buck Hale.
- [Crow] They are in space.
- [Joel] Look, look.
- [Crow] Ooh, what is it?
- [Joel] I hope it's one of ours.
- I have the mini satellite
on an infrared track.
- [Joel] Here it comes again.
- Touch down in two minutes.
- Let's hope the Mysterons
don't detect this one.
- [Joel] Let's hope they
have a strong defense.
- We're tracking them
by infrared reflection
of the sun's rays from
the satellite shell.
At least there's no transmission
for them to pick up.
- [Joel] Uh-oh, flying
meatball 10 o'clock.
- It's working perfecting,
right on target.
Minnesat Five is keeping the martian moon
between itself and the Mysterons.
- I've got a feeling it's gonna make it.
(suspenseful music)
(ship flame crackling)
- The retros are fired.
It's altered course as scheduled.
(suspenseful music)
- [Joel] It's a transformer.
It's heading straight
for us, oh, look out, oh.
- [Crow] That was a close one.
- [Joel] Oh, yeah.
Kind of looks like Cambot, doesn't it?
- [Crow] It does.
- It's landed.
We've done it.
- Wonderful.
Well, we've succeeded.
We've soft landed a small satellite
on the martian moon Phobus.
- And without the Mysterons detecting it.
- Right, Phobus orbits Mars
every 7 hours, 40 minutes
and our mini sat will get a free ride
right around the planet.
Every seven seconds it
will take a photograph.
These will be relayed back
to us at 0300 hours tonight
after its completed on orbit.
- Gentlemen, we're about to obtain
the best closeup shots of
Mars ever taken by man.
We have a lot of work ahead
and I suggest we all get some rest.
- Get some sleep as well, Captain Blue.
- I'll take the first watch, right.
- [Joel] Why do you think
they call him Captain Blue?
His language?
- [Crow] I think so.
I'm amazed they got Carey
Grant to do the voice
for this guy (laughs).
(suspenseful music)
(camera shuttering)
- [Joel] See, it's taking pictures Crow.
- [Crow] That's that.
(upbeat music)
(gentle music)
- [Joel] They really
keep it clean in there.
- [Servo] What's going on here, hmm.
- [Joel] Shh.
Come on over here.
(gentle music)
(suspenseful music)
- Who's there?
- It's only me.
Sorry if I startled you.
- Oh, Dr. Breck, I
thought you were in bed.
- Well, I couldn't sleep.
What time is it?
- Nearly midnight.
- Three hours to go.
The night's so clear, may I?
- Go ahead.
I was stargazing myself
before you came in.
- Mars.
The red planet.
- [Joel] Seems like a nice enough fellow.
- [Crow] At first.
- It was a brilliant idea to soft land
the mini sat on Phobas.
- Yes, it's course was carefully plotted,
so Phobus always shielded
the satellite from Mars.
That's why the Mysterons didn't locate it.
- Yes.
- Well, you might say we
worked in the shadow of fear.
- Fear?
- Yes, Phobus, the Greek word for fear.
The shadow of fear.
- Everything all right?
- Yes, Captain Blue.
- Well, it's midnight.
I'll take over the watch Captain Scarlet.
- Right, I'll get some sleep.
- I suggest you get some
rest, as well, Dr. Breck.
- All right, Captain, I think I will try
and get an hour or so.
- I'm gonna check outside.
Goodnight.
- Goodnight, Captain.
- [Joel] Doesn't Captain Blue look kind
of like Glen Campbell?
- [Crow] A little bit, yes.
- [Joel] A little bit country.
- [Crow] A little big rock and roll.
- [Servo] He's the purple stone cowboy.
(ominous music)
- The light?
It's so.
- [Servo] Bright?
- I can't...
I can't...
- [Joel] Sounds like?
- Compensating light.
- [Joel] Two syllables.
- [Servo] Shoulda bought a vowel.
(ominous music)
- [Joel] The Olympics rings.
- [Crow] What big zippers you have.
(Joel laughs)
- [Servo] Funny, his legs
don't move like a human.
(suspenseful music)
- [Joel] Uh-oh.
- Dr. Breck, are you all right?
- Fine, Captain, I'm fine.
- [Joel] Dr. Breck, the
shampoo genius, that's it.
- [Crow] He does have nice hair.
- What's our position, Leftenant Green?
- We're over flying the
Himalayas about eight miles west
of the observatory.
- Time?
- [Leftenant Green] 0158.
- Just over an hour to go.
Right, Leftenant.
Launch all angels.
- Angel One, immediate launch.
(jet firing)
Angels Two Three, immediate launch.
- [Servo] That must be Charlie.
- Maintain arrow
surveillance as instructed.
Observe radio silence
except in an emergency.
(jet whirring)
- [Joel] There it goes.
- All Angels sky born, sir.
- All we can do now wait.
The rest is up to the astronomers.
- Gone? He can't have gone.
I've looked everywhere.
- He's not in the observatory.
He just be found.
There's less than an
hour before transmission.
- His bed hasn't been slept in.
Dr. Breck is definitely
not in the building.
- I don't like it.
We're so close to success,
nothing must go wrong.
- [Servo] We've got
another hour and a half
to the movie, something has to.
- [Joel] Rotation gear housing.
It's filled with hula hoops, right?
- [Servo] You a cut up.
(ominous music)
- [Joel] It's the bubble bomb.
- [Servo] Do you want to
see my impression of that.
- [Joel] Hey, that's pretty good.
- [Servo] Thank you, I've been practicing.
- That's the position, Colonel
and there's less than 40 minutes to go.
- Breck is almost certainly
in the hands of the Mysterons.
But we must go ahead with the project.
I will order the spectrum
helicopter to fly
as low as possible over the area
in the hope that it may spot him.
Meantime, carry on with the preparations
for the transmission.
- Sig.
He can't have gone far Captain Blue.
We'll go outside and try and find him.
- Come Antolini, let's
get to the computer.
(ship whirring)
- [Crow] That's a
helicopter, not a computer.
(suspenseful music)
- I'm glad there's a moon.
- That's for sure.
Let's get a Mysteron
detector from the SPV.
- Test transmission in 10 seconds.
Five, four, three, zero.
- Bang on the nose, we're in business.
- Did you get a fix on the
beam width and flex density?
- Yes.
But we'll have to move the
aerial point 12 degrees.
- Right.
- We wait till the last minute
Just in case the Mysterons are trying
to pinpoint our position.
- He could be anywhere.
- Right, we better keep looking.
Time is running out.
(suspenseful music)
- Start transmission countdown.
(counter clicking)
- [Joel] Can you imagine all the stations.
(suspenseful music)
- That could be him.
- Captain Sky, I think
Captain Gray has located them.
We're going around for another look.
- [Servo] Ooh, doggie.
- Yes, we found him.
He's in the rocks about the observatory.
- SIG Melody.
Well, Captain Blue, he's
in the rocks of Phobas.
- Let's go.
- Check video.
- Video positive.
(counter clicking)
We'll traverse the area at
transmission minus 40 seconds.
(triumphant music)
- Breck.
We know you're up there Breck.
All right, we're coming to take you.
(gun firing)
- [Servo] Ooh, they got me, ooh, ooh.
Sorry.
- Don't be stupid, Breck.
Give up before it's too late.
- It's already too late for you earthmen.
- What does that mean?
- I've planted a bomb in
the radio telescope's rotation gear.
When it's turned, the observatory
will be blown to pieces.
You will never beat us.
(gun firing)
- Ah!
- [Crow] (laughing) He got him.
- We've got to warn them.
- There's no time.
- We must try.
- [Joel] You know that
puppet does his own stunts.
- [Crow] Does he really?
- Stand by to rotate aerials.
- [Cambot] I personally don't believe
that puppets should be on TV.
(suspenseful music)
- Five seconds.
Rotate aerial.
- [Crow] Don't do it.
- Picture transmission in 30 seconds.
- [Crow] Well, that's a list a thing bomb.
- This time we're gonna do it.
- [Servo] Ooh, doggie.
(building exploding)
(doors slamming)
- Okay, come here.
Hey, Gypsy, come on over here,
yeah, come here.
Okay, do you see these gourds I got here.
- Yeah?
- Okay, now these gourds
are what we usually put
in a cornucopia, okay?
Back on earth.
- A cornucopia?
- Yeah, a cornucopia is this thing,
it's kind of shaped like a horn,
like you're not getting this are you.
Wait a minute, just come on over here,
put your head down.
Can I use your mouth to demonstrate
what a cornucopia is?
- A cornucopia?
- Yeah, a cornucopia.
It's also known, just open
your mouth us, that's good.
It's also known as a horn of plenty.
And around Thanksgiving time on Earth
we take these horn of plenties
and fill them up with
gourds and put them around
kind of as a centerpiece.
- A centerpiece?
- Yeah, to show people
that it's been a good year,
that we've had plenty.
I think you're starting
to get it, you know that?
- Hello, Joel Hodgson.
- Hey, Crow.
- Giving Gypsum another one
of your famous food revs.
- No, good one Crow.
You're getting better, no,
it's nothing like that.
I'm making Gypsum's mouth
into a horn of plenty.
- Oh.
- It's a way of showing on earth
that we've had enough.
(Gypsum squealing)
- I think Gypsum just invented
a way to show she's had enough.
- Right?
Are you okay?
Okay, we're gonna break
for a commercial now.
Why don't you go make a sandwich
or something? All right.
(upbeat music)
(satellite beeping)
- [Servo] Mm, those
commercials were pretty good.
- K14 observatory has
been completely destroyed.
There is no chance of
there being any survivors.
- [Joel] Jackie Gleason.
- This is lunar control.
- You see his face?
- [Colonel White] Since man's
first successful landing
on the moon back in the 1970s,
we have gradually learn to live
on this barren, apparently
uninviting world-
- 1970s?
- In safety and comfort.
- At present, there are some
4,000 men and women living
and working on the lunar service.
The earth is engaged in
a savage war of nerves
with the Mysterons.
This is none of our doing
and we want no part of it.
I wish to announce that I have been able
to contact the Mysterons,
to communicate with them
and come to a peaceful settlement.
This is not our fight.
The moon does not take sides,
but we will not support the earth
against the Mysterons.
How was the transmission?
- It seemed fine.
Ask the computer, sir.
- [Colonel White] How was
the transmission, SID?
- [SID] Transmission strength
and definition excellent.
Predict reception around the
moon and on earth exceptional.
- [Servo] That sounded like
my second grade teacher.
- Members of Spectrum.
You have all heard or read
last night's transmission
by the lunar controller
in which he declared the moon
an independent world.
- Is he legally entitled
to do this, Colonel?
- We're not concerned with the legality
of the situation, Captain.
The Spectrum's main purpose
is to counter the Mysteron threat.
That is our basic function.
One part of the lunar
controller's announcement
was to particular significance.
Leftenant Green will read
the relevant section.
- Holt, I have been able
to contact the Mysterons.
- [Joel] Hey, is that a
Grateful Dead pin he's got on.
- To counter peaceful settlement and port.
- [Servo] I think it is.
- Can we believe what he says?
- [Crow] And that looks
bad about the shoulders.
- I don't know, Captain Blue.
But I do know that we cannot afford
to disbelieve it.
The Spectrum would be very interested
to come to terms with the Mysterons.
If the lunar controller has
succeeded, we want to know how.
If he hasn't, we want to know
the reason for his deception.
- Could he be a Mysteron agent, sir?
- This cannot be ruled out, Captain.
- [Joel] Doesn't he look
like "The Man from Glad?"
- But there is only one place
we will find the answer.
- [Crow] Nice hair, buddy.
- In Lunarville Seven.
(dramatic music)
- [Man] T-minus 10.
- XK5 to control.
Internal countdown complete.
Five, four, three, two, one, zero.
- Stand by for liftoff.
- [Servo] This movie needs
more countdowns in it.
I just cannot get enough.
(base exploding)
Joel?
- [Joel] What?
- [Servo] How come you gave me such
a funny voice when you made me?
- [Joel] It reminded me of
my second grade teacher.
- [Servo] Good answer, Joel.
- Hike 20,000 feet.
- [Joel] Hey, nice hat, guy.
- Speed 6.5 miles per second.
Escape velocity.
- Well, we're on our way.
- SIG, Captain Scarlet.
We are leaving the earth's atmosphere.
Accelerate to 100,000 MPH.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Boy, that moon looks
like Jackie Gleason, doesn't it?
- [Crow] Mm-hmm.
- Colonel White, XK3 is
in orbit around the moon.
Lunar rocket separation in four minutes.
- Right.
Put me in direct contact
with Captain Scarlet.
- Sig.
- This is Colonel White.
As the lunar controller
has banned personal radios
nor other equipment, I'll give you
your final instructions now.
- [Man] Yes, Colonel.
- We have reports that a
new unauthorized complex
is being constructed in the Humbalt Sea
on the far side of the moon.
This must be investigated.
- I have the map reference, sir.
We'll do everything possible.
- I don't have to tell you how important
this assignment is.
The future of the world
may well be in your hands.
Do you all understand?
- [Servo] Look, Joel, I'm a lever.
- Sig.
- [Colonel White] Captain, Blue?
- [Colonel White] Captain Scarlet.
- Sig.
- [SID] The Spectrum
personnel in the moon rocket
have left the parking orbit.
They will dock as they
agree in four minutes.
- Thank you, SID.
- Go and meet them Orson.
This is their first visit to the moon.
- And their last, Controller?
- Yes, Orson, it could well be their last.
(Joel laughing)
(ominous music)
- [Joel] Oh, Charles,
get away from the blast.
- Let's get into the air lock.
- [Servo] Get it, Joe, get it.
- [Man] The walkway is in position.
Open the outer door.
- Right, opening now.
- My name's Orson.
I'm the lunar controller's PA.
- We would like to see
the lunar controller
as soon as possible.
- I'll take you to him immediately.
Please wear these recognition discs.
(dramatic music)
- May I welcome you to Lunarville Seven.
- Thank you, sir, we're glad to be here.
- You have already met my personal aid.
Let me introduce our control computer.
His code name is SID.
Speech Intelligence Decoder.
He is programmed to understand
and obey verbal instructions
and can answer with his
own simulated voice.
Say hello, Sid.
- [SID] Good day, Captain Scarlet.
- [Servo] Oh, hello SID.
- [SID] Good day, Leftenant Green.
- He recognizes you by
the badges you're wearing.
Ask him a question, go ahead.
- What is the outside temperature?
- [SID] 2 degrees centigrade,
35.6 degrees Fahrenheit,
275.16 absolute.
- Very thorough.
- Yes, SID controls
everything in Lunarville.
The air conditioning, air
locks, power supplies, even-
- [Servo] The plot.
- The rockets and moon mobiles.
- A very important piece of equipment.
- Assembled entirely on the
moon by our own technicians.
- But designed and developed on earth.
- The earth may have helped us,
but now we are self-reliant, democratic
and free, understand.
- Well, forgive me gentlemen.
- He's kind of tight.
- Yes.
- I was told you have a message
from the world president.
- Yes, sir, they asked me to hand you
this letter personally.
- [Crow] It's from Ed McMahon.
- I'll study it and give you my answer.
- [Servo] You may have already won.
- [Man] Please ask Orson.
- Gentlemen, I'm at your service.
- As this is our first visit,
we would appreciate a trip
out on the lunar surface.
- [Man] Certainly, SID.
- [Servo] Right this way.
- [SID] Yes, Mr. Orson.
- Have a moon mobile ready
at air lock number three immediately.
- [SID] The moon mobile will be available
at air lock three at once.
- If you will follow me, gentlemen.
- [Crow] This should be good.
- Please fasten your safety belts.
The unusual most can be disturbing
until you become used to it.
- [Servo] That is unusual.
(aircraft hissing)
- [Joel] Looks like
it's running out of gas.
- [Crow] Oh, give me a break.
- It's certainly a novel
method of transportation
and surprisingly smooth.
- The earth's gravity
is six times stronger
than the moons'.
A machine like this would
be useless on earth.
The force of impact on
landing would be too great.
- Look, another lunar station.
- Lunarville four.
Most of our food is grown there.
- That must use a great deal of water.
The moon has no natural water.
But first all supplies were
transported from earth.
But the component elements,
hydrogen and oxygen.
- [Crow] And cheese.
- We can now synthesize more than enough
for our own needs.
- Let's see.
If I remember the map correctly,
our present course would
take us to the Humbalt Sea.
- What is your interest in that area?
- Oh, a natural curiosity.
- It's on the far side of the moon,
never visible from earth.
- And it's 200 miles away.
- We have plenty of time.
- I'm afraid not.
- We would appreciate.
- No.
- I'm sorry, maybe another time.
It's late.
We should return to Lunarville Seven.
- [Servo] Something is afoot.
- [Crow] I think it's the
thing on the end of your leg.
- [Servo] You sure are
funny for an ugly robot.
I love that.
- This will be your suite for
the duration of your stay.
- [Joel] Looks like a George Jetson house.
- [Servo] Jane, stop this crazy thing.
- [Captain Scarlet] I'm sure
we'll be most comfortable.
- I'll leave you then.
You must be tired.
If the earth light is too bright,
the control for the polarity
window is near the door.
- Did you notice his reaction
when you mentioned the Humbalt Sea?
- He bolted.
I think I'll just take a look around.
The room is probably bugged, keep talking.
- You know I found that trip
in the moon mobile most interesting.
I never realized how
complex the installations
are on the moon.
- [Servo] It's down here, it's down here.
- [Leftenant Scarlet]
Leftenant Green, do you agree?
- Yes, the synthesis of water
from its component elements
must have been a great breakthrough.
- How many people do you think the moon
is capable of supporting?
- [Leftenant Green] Well,
all the elements vital
to human life
are found on or near the lunar surface,
so I think the number is very high.
- I think I found it, keep quiet.
- Good night Orson.
- [Orson] Ah!
- Right, I think we can now discuss
the situation without being overheard.
- [Joel] Who says puppets don't have
a sense of humor.
- What is it Orson?
- Scarlet discovered the microphone.
- [Servo] I would never day that.
- Let them make their futile plans.
I have programmed SID to
accept only my authorization.
He will keep all exits sealed.
Let them plot Orson.
They're trapped on Lunarville Seven.
We will deal with them at our leisure.
- [Servo] Maybe after a Jacuzzi.
(dramatic music)
- [SID] Who is there?
Identify yourself or I
must sound the alarm.
- I am Captain Scarlet.
- [SID] Thank you, Captain Scarlet.
Can I help you?
- I require a moon mobile immediately.
- [SID] I am sorry, your recognition disc
cannot authorize a moon mobile.
- Well, who has the authority?
- [SID] In the present emergency,
only the lunar controller.
- Emergency?
- [SID] The lunar controller has declared
a state of emergency.
Lunarville Seven has been evacuated.
All except class three instructions
need his authorization.
- I see.
I'll ask for his permission when he wakes.
- [SID] This would be important.
Good rest Captain Scarlet.
- Goodnight, SID.
- [Servo] Goodnight, SID.
- [Joel] Goodnight, SID.
- [Crow] Who's SID?
- Captain Blue, wake up.
- What is it?
- The lunar controller
has declared an emergency.
Lunarville Seven has been evacuated.
- [Joel] Nice PJs Captain Blue.
- If only we had a Mysteron detector,
we could be sure.
- Yes, but we never
would have been allowed
to land with one.
- Well, what do you suggest?
- We must get a moon mobile
and check out the Humbalt Sea.
The answer may be there.
- Easier said than done.
- I'll take care of it.
Wake Leftenant Green and
meet me at air lock three.
(Leftenant Green snoring)
(upbeat music)
- How'd you get Sid to let us out?
- I'll explain later.
You think you can handle the controls?
- Yes, I'll manage.
- Leftenant Green, have
you got that map reference.
- Yes, Captain Scarlet.
- Right, you will act as navigator.
- Sig.
- Let's go.
- [Joel] He sure is bossy.
- [Servo] Let's go to the hop.
Thank you.
- What's our ETA as the Humbalt Sea?
- 0400 hours.
- Two hours. We might
just have time to get back
before the lunar controller
discovers we're gone.
- [Servo] He's got a pack of Marlboros.
(Joel coughing)
- [Servo] A hunka hunka burning moon rock.
(ship hissing)
- Well, we've covered the whole area
and found absolutely nothing.
Another 10 minutes, then we'll start back.
- I thought I saw a light.
- [Colonel] Where?
- About two miles ahead.
15 degrees to port.
- [Colonel] I don't see anything.
- Wait, but look, there it is again.
- Yes, it's coming from a small crater.
Must be here.
It's marked but unnamed crater 101.
Let's get over there and investigate.
- [Servo] It's you, Joel.
- What can it be?
- From the amount of dust,
there's a lot of activity down there.
- We'll soon know.
(satellite hissing)
- Stop the moon mobile.
- [Joel] Looks like a
giant pinball machine.
- And those vehicles there,
moving in such strange patterns.
- You're the electronics
expert, Leftenant,
what do you think?
- They must be unmanned.
They pattern is a complicated program.
They've been program to
carried out a set task.
- They seem to be doodling something.
- [Servo] What's a leftenant?
- There is no possible doubt,
exactly as the film from
the MEV on Mars showed it.
- A Mysteron complex
and it looks near completion.
We've seen enough.
We must get back to Lunarville Seven
and report this to cloud base.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Looks like the micro brewery.
- They can't have gone.
- I assure you, sir.
- When? How?
- I don't know, I went
into their room and-
- I'm not interested in details.
Send out every available man.
They must be found.
- You ordered the evacuation
of Lunarville Seven, sir.
Everyone's left.
- The moon mobile has just
gone past phase there.
Captain Scarlet, Captain
Blue and Lieutenant Green
have entered Lunarville Seven.
- They've come back.
Of course, bring them here at once.
- Yes, sir.
- What they have seen must
never get back to earth.
Bring them here.
- There's no need lunar controller.
On the assumption that his first note
will be rejected and subject
to our investigation,
the world president authorized me
to place you under close arrest
and escort you back to earth.
- Arrest me?
You are fools earthmen.
Already a complex is being built.
Soon the Mysteron will
come to take over the moon
and then the earth.
- We have seen the complex
and it will be destroyed.
- No, you will never leave the moon alive,
any of you.
- Sid.
Prepare a lunar rocket
for immediate launch.
We are leaving at once for the Earth.
- Don't waste your breath.
- A lunar rocket is ready at phase three.
- No, SID, this is the lunar controller.
Seal all exits.
- Come on.
- [Crow] Er, er.
- I am giving you an order.
- [Servo] See it?
Never mind.
- Let's go.
- I command you, seal all exits.
- [Joel] Okay, I get it.
- It's not use good lunar controller,
SID cannot identify you.
- [Servo] I figured you would.
- I changed recognition
discs with you last night.
- SID, this is the lunar controller.
Stop them.
Seal all exits.
- [SID] I'm sorry seal recognition disc
cannot authorize that.
- Obey, obey.
Seal all exits.
- [SID] I am sorry, your recognition disc
does not authorize that.
- Enter the air lock.
The rocket's ready for launch.
- This is your last chance, SID.
Seal all exits.
- [SID] I am sorry, your recognition disc.
(gun fires)
I am sorry.
- [Joel] I hate the sight of oil.
- Come on, let's get out of here.
- [Servo] Makes me cringe.
- Obey!
(gun fires)
- [Joel] All right, already.
- [Crow] You know there
was an off switch, dummo.
(Joel laughing)
- [SID] I am sorry.
- [Crow] I'm sorry you had to see that.
It wasn't pretty.
- [Servo] I'm all choked up.
- [Joel] There goes that micro brewery.
- [Crow] I only hope they get the writer.
- Take off.
(rocket exploding)
- [Servo] There's still a
little cone in front of me.
Yay.
- Stop the picture.
There's no possible doubt.
That shot proves conclusively-
- [Joel] Looks like a bunch
of giant martinis in the background.
- The far side of the moon houses
a Mysteron Complex.
- Yes, Colonel, we were shocked-
- [Servo] I think they're gin an tonics.
- Must, of course, be
destroyed as soon as possible.
- When do we leave, sir?
- Wait, there's something else.
Here's the plan.
It has been decided to
divide the operation
into two distinct assignments.
- Two assignments, Colonel?
- Yes, Captain Blue.
The second is to destroy
the Mysteron complex.
Arrangements have been made
with the lunar authorities
to carry this out.
- And the first?
- The first is more dangerous.
It involves a calculated
risk of the first magnitude.
- [Joel] Combing your hair?
- If we tried to destroy that complex-
- [Servo] No, leaving his chair.
- Presumably the Mysterons
will use their powers
to reconstruct it.
Therefore, it has been decided
to send a volunteer party into crater 101
into the Mysteron complex.
Objective, to find and remove
the power source from the complex.
(dramatic music)
Right, you've all had time to consider.
As I said, this assignment
is on a volunteer basis.
Your decisions can be made
in the strictest confidence.
- I'm ready to go, sir.
- Thank you, Leftenant.
As the electronics expert you will play
a vital part in the operation.
- Count me in, sir.
- Thank you, Captain.
I know I can rely on you.
- Well, Colonel, I am due
for 48 hours furlough in Miami,
but I couldn't really relax knowing
the kind of trouble these two
would get into without me.
(Joel laughs)
I'm ready, Colonel.
- [Servo] Heba, heba.
- Thank you, Captain Scarlet.
Well, gentlemen, no one knows who or what
you will find inside that complex.
All that remains for me
to do is to wish you luck.
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] That gives me a headache.
- This is a scale model of crater 101
and the surrounding area.
It was built up from
extensive aerial recognizance
over the past few days.
- What do we know about the vehicles
which were building the complex?
- They are unmanned lunar vehicles,
programmed to carry out the task.
This larger one controls the operation.
- We don't know how or
when all this was started.
- The lunar controller
was a Mysteron agent.
The secret died with him
when Lunarville Seven was destroyed.
- Well, the plan of attack is obvious.
Knock out the control vehicle,
then tackle the complex.
- We have decided to use
a low yield atomic device
to destroy the complex after
you have had time to investigate it.
- Good. When do we leave?
- At once.
You will travel by moon mobile.
- [Servo] Nice glasses.
- It will only take two hours.
And the arrangements-
- [Joel] They look like swimming goggles.
- Yes, Ms. Noland.
I will follow the moon mobile.
- [Servo] Can puppets swim?
- This will be positioned in the crater
and the detonator set for midnight,
standard earth time.
- Good.
That gives you six hours Captain Scarlet,
two to get to crater 101
and four hours to remove the power source
and get clear.
- Right, we're on our way.
- Captain Scarlet.
- Yes, Ms. Noland.
- I'd like you to take this.
It's a lucky charm.
I'm not really superstitious,
but please take it.
- To Linda Noland, the CB29 Neptune probe,
July 10, 2058.
We made it ahead of schedule.
- I remember.
You were the project controller
on the first Neptune probe
launched from the moon.
- Yes, Captain Blue.
- [Captain Blue] Let's
home we're as successful.
- Be careful, Captain.
- Don't worry, we intend to come back.
Let's go.
- [Servo] I need to go to
some radiator maintenance.
- A brave man.
And very good looking.
- Who?
- Captain Scarlet.
- Yes, I suppose so, I
didn't really notice.
- Yes, Ms. Noland.
(ominous music)
(moon mobile hissing)
- ETA crater 101, 55 minutes.
- It's time for you to leave, Frazier.
- Yes, Ms. Noland.
- Remember, set the
detonator for midnight SET.
We must give them time to get clear.
Frazier?
Frazier, are you all right?
- Yes, I'm fine.
Your instructions will be carried out.
(dramatic music)
(upbeat music)
- If the turkey comes out of his hole
and sees his shadow,
that means we have six
more weeks of Easter?
- No, Crow, it's not like this.
Back at my house when I was on Earth,
we would have Thanksgiving
dinner around 2 o'clock,
have mashed potatoes, turkey, yams,
the whole shebang.
Then around dinner time,
around six or seven, we'd
have turkey sandwiches
even if we weren't hungry.
Then later that night my
mom would cut up the turkey
some more and put it in
Tupperware for the drive home.
- And for breakfast turkey crisp cereal?
- Right.
- I'm right?
You see that time I
was trying to be funny.
I'm never going to catch on.
- Crow, I was just kidding,
I was just getting into it,
like I would say
cocoa-flavored Thanksgiving,
you get it?
- (laughs) Oh, very funny Joel Hodgson.
Don't forget Kellogg's beaks and feet.
- Right, or raisins, rice and giblets.
Hi, Servo.
(talking over each other)
Great.
- Hmm, let's see, things
that are in a mattress.
Things that have somebody for dessert.
Things that Dick Clark
might say in his sleep.
- No, toasted turkey trots Servo.
- Things you might say on a TV show
if you were trying to take up time.
- Moto turkey.
- Things you might eat for breakfast
the day after Thanksgiving
if you were just kidding.
- Right, you got it.
Oh, we got movie siren,
guys, we gotta get out here.
Cheese it.
(doors clanking)
- I am aboard the lunar tank
and ready to leave.
- Right.
Report in an hour, Frazier.
We're tracking okay now.
(tank whirring)
- [Joel] Hey, Crow.
Hey, Servo.
Hmm, he's big.
- [Crow] He could use a Q-tip, too.
- I have Captain Scarlet
on the inner space radio link, sir.
- Good, let me speak to him.
Captain Scarlet?
- Yes, Colonel.
We're about the cross the lunar horizon.
We will then be on the far
side of the moon from earth
and we lose all radio contact.
- I understand, Captain.
What's the latest situation?
- When we arrive at the crater,
we will immobilize the control vehicle
and then enter the complex.
After our investigation,
the whole area will be
destroyed at midnight
standard earth time.
- SIG, Captain.
Report back as soon as the
radio link is restored.
- [Servo] What's SIG?
- Sig.
- What are the chances, sir?
- [Joel] He gets a cigarette
if he does it right.
- Men have faced the unknown before,
but I believe no man has ever faced
what awaits them in crater 101.
- [Servo] Carol Mastro.
- [Joel] Carol Marrow.
Crater number one.
- [Crow] Take the box.
- It's just over this ridge.
- Sig.
(ominous music)
- Stop the moon mobile.
Look.
- [Crow] It's a Tupperware party.
- [Joel] A giant vacuum cleaner.
- [Crow] That puts out dust.
- Well, it answers one
question, how to get in.
- You mean, we are going the same way?
- Yes, Leftenant.
Let's get into the moon tractor.
- [Joel] Disguised as dust balls.
- [Servo] I found being a dust bunny
can get you into a lot of places.
- [Crow] I can see the string.
- We've got to knock out
that control vehicle.
- They're going to attack.
- [Servo] Scrubbing bubbles.
- Lieutenant Green, man the missile gun.
Look out, Captain Blue.
- [Crow] I hate to see what
they'd do to a bathtub.
- There's another, swerve.
- [Servo] Zig.
- Can you see the control vehicle?
- There's so much dust.
- There it is, dead ahead.
- Fire.
- Missed.
Don't lose sight of it.
Stop!
(machine crashes)
- [Servo] It's like a tractor
pull kind of. (Joel laughs)
- [Servo] They'll turn the moon
into a giant mud pit.
- We're stuck.
- [Captain Blue] Look, it's coming back.
- Keep trying.
- It's no good, it won't budge.
- It'll smash us to pieces.
- There's the control vehicle.
- [Joel] You want some popcorn?
- [Crow] Yes, please.
- You have one chance left,
Leftenant, don't miss.
(gun fires)
(machines hissing)
- Do I get a coconut?
- If we ever get out of this Leftenant,
I'll buy you all the coconuts you can eat.
- Lunarville Six to lunar tank,
what is your position?
- I am about to cross the lunar horizon.
- Right.
Remember, set the detonator
for 12 o'clock SET.
- I am sorry, earth woman.
- Earth woman?
- The detonator is already set for 10,
two hours earlier than Spectrum think.
- Frazier, listen to me Frazier.
- Captain Scarlet is below
the lunar horizon.
You cannot contact him.
He will die in crater 101.
- Lieutenant Green's
freed the lunar tractor.
We're ready to go.
- Good.
And there's Frazier in the
atomic device right on time.
(dramatic music)
Tell Lieutenant Green to get back in here.
- Sig.
- Captain Scarlet to lunar
tank, come in Frazier.
- I'm about to release the atomic device.
- [Captain Scarlet] Right,
we'll start the investigation.
- Good luck.
- [Joel] I'm gonna put the rest
of the popcorn in your head.
- Goodbye earth man.
- [Servo] I was hoping you'd say that.
- [Joel] We'll save it for later.
(dramatic music)
- [Servo] Traction,
traction, action, action.
- [Joel] Power, power, power.
- [Crow] I bet they're all tankful
they got out of that.
- [Joel] Good one, Crow.
- [Crow] Sorry.
- [Colonel] Radio check,
Captain Blue, spectrum is green.
Leftenant, radio is-
- [Servo] Care for a
stove full of popcorn.
- [Colonel] Let's go in.
- [Captain Blue] Through the wall?
- [Colonel] Through the wall.
- [Joel] It won't come around.
- It's indescribable.
- Start the cameras, let's move on.
- [Joel] Those Mysterons
sure know how to decorate.
- [Crow] Psychedelic.
- [Joel] Kind of like Peter Max was there.
- [Servo] Purple haze all in my brain.
- [Colonel] Take it easy, Leftenant,
you're forgetting the low gravity.
- Sig.
- There's no radiation.
What's the temperature?
- Normal.
Gravity and pressure fluctuation negative.
- [Servo] No pressure fluctuation.
- No trace of any x-ray
or infrared emission?
- No, nothing so far.
Where's Leftenant Green?
Leftenant Green?
- [Joel] They got him.
He's a Mysteron.
- Over there.
- Leftenant Green, what's wrong?
- [Joel] That was assy.
- [Servo] I know.
- [Servo] Joel, make a bunny shadow.
(gun fires)
- [Servo] He doesn't like bunny shadows.
- Another few seconds
and we would have all been transfixed.
- I couldn't look away.
I tried, but I just couldn't.
- Let's move in and stay together.
- [Joel] Good.
- Frazier is a Mysteron?
- Are you sure Contrilla?
- He told me as much himself.
He set the detonator for
10 o'clock instead of 12.
- What?
Isn't there some way we
can warn Captain Scarlet?
- No, he's out of radio range.
- [Joel] Radio range?
Isn't that a kind of stove.
- Stay back.
- [Captain Blue] What is it, Captain?
- Some kind of weightless area just
in front of where you're standing.
- [Servo] He's going up
to the Jetsons' apartment.
- [Crow] Astro dog like.
- Captain Scarlet, can you hear me?
- Yes, it's all right, you can come up.
I think I've found the
heart of the complex.
- [Joel] Sure helps you float when you've
got threads on you.
- Through there.
- [Crow] That's right.
- Look.
What is it?
- There's only one way to find out.
- [Joel] Shoot it.
(mysterious music)
- [Crow] Be careful, it's
the worst special effect yet.
- [Servo] This could be trouble.
- [Crow] Place your bets, place your bets.
- [Joel] They're trying to
legalize gambling on the moon.
- My instrumentation's gone crazy.
- [Joel] It's a lottery.
- The power source.
- Get as many pictures as you can.
We've got to work fast.
Remember the 12 o'clock deadline.
- Well, a rocket's the
only thing fast enough
to get there before that bomb explodes.
- An unmanned rocket.
Could it work?
There's the slimmest chance,
but it's the only one.
- Right, we've got enough pictures.
What time is it?
- 9:32 set.
- Good.
Two and a half hours to detonation,
we have plenty of time.
- [Servo] Funny how two and a half hours
seems like 30 minutes.
- The rocket is ready on the launch pad.
- Start the countdown immediately.
- [Crow] Good, another countdown.
- All we can do now is hope.
- [Servo] Well, you sure can't fart.
- Four, three, two, one, lift off.
(rocket exploding)
- [Crow] Got carried away.
- I'm going to try and
remove the power source.
- Take it easy, Captain.
(rocket whirring)
- What was that?
- I don't know. I'll go and find out.
- [Servo] I could sure use
a good commercial right now.
(dramatic music)
(upbeat music)
- [Colonel] Can you see
anything Captain Blue?
- Yes.
It's an unmanned space probe.
And old CB29.
It must have been launched
from Lunarville Six.
- But why an obsolete CB29?
Unless...
- Maybe it's some kind of message.
- Or a warning?
- Nah.
- The lucky charm.
- What was it?
To Linda Noland, the CB29 Neptune probe
July 10, 2058.
- We made it ahead of schedule.
Can you see a connection?
- [Servo] That schedule.
- Ahead of schedule.
- [Joel] Schedule!
- 12 o'clock SET.
The bomb.
It could mean the bomb will
explode ahead of schedule.
- [Servo] You just said it Leftenant.
- Captain Blue, check the detonator time
on that atomic device.
- [Captain Blue] SIG.
- Leftenant Green, get
back in the moon mobile.
- But Captain.
- That's an order.
- [Crow] Dano, check out every
license number on the planet.
- Get moving.
- Sig.
- [Joel] SIG.
- [Crow] I think it's a
Johnny Quest thing, SIG.
- [Joel] Oh, that's it.
- Captain Scarlet, the
detonator is set for 10.
Get out of there.
The whole crater will
go up in five minutes.
- Get into the moon mobile.
I'll follow as soon as I can.
- [Servo] How can a crater go up?
- I'm coming back.
- No, at least get the cameras to safety.
- [Captain Blue] Captain Scarlet.
- You know I'm right, Adam, do as I say.
- Spectrum is green.
- [Crow] That would just make it level.
(ominous music)
- Less than two minutes to detonation.
- [Joel] Just pretend you're using
one of those cranes at the state fair.
- We're safe here.
Any sign of Captain Scarlet?
- No, nothing.
(dramatic music)
(crater exploding)
- [Servo] The crater.
- [Crow] It went up.
- He didn't make it.
He just didn't make it.
- Look.
- [Man] What a guy.
- [Servo] I tended to doubt it myself.
- Well, gentlemen, I'm glad to be able
to tell you mission accomplished.
- Our recognizance shows
it was a complete success.
- That's great news.
It means that the Mysteron
powers of reconstruction
of somehow connected
with this power source.
We must take it back to earth at once.
Well, I'm afraid it's goodbye.
Thank you for everything.
- [Crow] No, I'm afraid it's a diamond.
- Goodbye, Captain Scarlet.
- I almost forgot, your lucky charm.
- I'd take it as a favor if you'd keep it.
- Thank you.
Let's go Adam.
- I think she likes him.
(gentle music)
- [Servo] Too bad she lives on the moon.
- A brave man and so good looking.
- I suppose so.
I didn't think you'd notice.
(upbeat music)
- I'm going down to the lounge.
Let me know when Captain
Scarlet makes contact
with Dr. Kernitz.
And launch Angel One to escort
them back to cloud base.
- Yes, Colonel.
(triumphant music)
- [Man] Angel One, immediate launch.
- Sig.
(plane soaring)
- Receipt of grid reference G17
on away to arrival of Captain
Scarlet and Dr. Kernitz.
- You will escort them back to cloud base.
This is a maximum security operation.
- SIG, Lieutenant Green.
I shall take good care of them.
I know how important this mission is.
- [Joel] Sounds like she knows.
Nice stereo.
(Servo coughing)
You okay?
- Popcorn.
- [Joel] The T94.
Compact disc.
(dramatic music)
(triumphant music)
- Leftenant Green, I'm outside
the Nash Institute of Technology.
- The helicopter reports
you were not followed.
Proceed Captain Scarlet.
Dr. Kernitz is expecting you.
- Sig.
(Servo squeaking)
- Excuse me.
- Yes?
- [Woman] Captain Scarlet
has arrived, Dr. Kernitz.
- [Dr. Kernitz] Good, tell
the Captain I am ready
to leave immediately.
- The doctor will be with
you in a minute, sir.
He says he's ready to leave at once.
- Good, thank you.
Captain Scarlet to Yellow Fox.
Proceed to rear entrance
of research center.
- Spectrum is green.
(vehicle engine revving)
- Ready doctor?
- Ready.
- You have everything?
- Yes.
(dramatic music)
A gasoline tanker?
- I think you'll find it comfortable.
After you, Dr. Kernitz.
- Thank you, Captain.
- [Crow] They're gonna
get tanked, tanked, Joel.
- [Joel] Good one, Crow.
- Dr. Kernitz and I have
rendezvoused with Yellow Fox.
ETA at the airport minus 20 minutes.
- Sig.
The Spectrum helicopter will over fly
the route to the airport.
And Angel aircraft will escort
your plane to cloud base.
- SIG, Leftenant Green.
- Very ingenious.
We can fly in comfort
and complete secrecy.
- That's right, Doctor.
Spectrum have found the tank very useful.
- [Joel] Kind of like a Yugo.
Comfort and complete secrecy.
Well, maybe.
- [Crow] You know, we
could use another countdown
right about now.
- Well, Doctor, what are
the results of your tests?
- I know the danger you
went through Captain Scarlet
to get the pulsator,
but I can tell you know it was worth it.
Because of your efforts,
I believe we will be able
to communicate with the Mysterons.
Let's hope they will listen to reason.
- [Mysteron] This is the
voice of the Mysterons.
We know that you can hear us earthmen.
Our next act of retaliation
will be to destroy cloud base.
Do you hear?
Spectrum's headquarters cloud base
will be destroyed at midnight.
- [Servo] Joel, you never moved your lips.
- Well, Colonel, the Mysterons
plan to destroy cloud base.
- Yes, Captain.
It's incredible they
should choose such a time.
But as this base is already
on maximum security alert.
There's very little more that we can do.
Except to ensure that
security arrangements
are carried out.
- Yes, Colonel.
- No one will be allowed to
leave or board cloud base.
And the entire craft will be subjected
to hourly searches with
Mysteron detectives.
- This is already being done, sir.
- Good.
Any plane, rocket or satellite approaching
within a 50-mile radius will be attacked.
The only exceptions to this
are the aircraft bringing Dr. Kernitz
and Captain Scarlet to cloud base.
- Spectrum have done a good job
on the transmission circuits, Colonel.
- Thank you, Doctor.
- It was built exactly
to the circuit diagrams
you sent us and it's been fully tested.
- Well, let's get on with it.
- Allow me doctor.
- [Dr. Kernitz] Certainly, Captain.
- [Captain] Did it.
- Good, switch on the primary seconds.
- Right.
- Pulsating.
Just as it did on the Mysteron complex
on the moon.
- Yes, Captain Blue.
With the aid of the photographs,
you can Captain Scarlet took,
it was relatively easy to assimilate
the exact conditions inside that complex.
- Is it going to work Doctor?
- I am certain it will.
Give me a couple of hours
to check the secondary circuits
and the frequency and for the first time,
you Colonel White will
be able to speak directly
to the Mysterons.
(dramatic music)
- What time is it, Leftenant.
- [Leftenant Green] 1100 hours, sir.
- 13 hours to midnight.
- [Leftenant Green]
Captain Blue is here here.
- Anything to report Captain Blue?
- Have the Mysteron
detectives revealed anything?
- No, Colonel.
The whole base has been checked out
and except for the diamond pulsator,
of course, there's nothing.
- The Mysteron said they
would destroy cloud base at midnight.
We must maintain a constant vigil.
There is little else we can do.
- Well, let's hope the
Mysterons listen to reason
when you talk to them.
- Yes, a transmission.
The future of the world
could well depend on that.
- 58 seconds to transmission.
- All circuits AOK.
- 10 seconds.
- Stand by, Colonel.
- Spectrum is green.
- Five, four, three,
two, one, transmission.
- This is Colonel White
commander in chief of Spectrum,
speaking on behalf of
the people's the earth
to the Mysterons on Mars.
I would like to recall man's
first survey expedition
on the surface of your planet.
The martian exploration vehicle landed
to try and discover more
about the universe we live in.
Inside, three men from
earth, nervous, alert
and then they discovered your complex.
- [Mysteron] The first of
the earth's space traveler's have arrived.
They, too, have a curiosity about
the universe we live in.
We must welcome them.
- [Crow] From here they were being good.
- [Mysteron] Let us take a closer look.
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] Good.
- They're obviously hostile.
- Okay, Leftenant, let 'em have it.
(laser blasting)
- [Crow] And they're calling them hostile?
- Then, for the first time
men from earth witnessed
your amazing powers of reconstruction.
- [Joel] It seems like they understand
the weather pretty good, too.
Looks like a Barbie dream house.
- [Mysteron] Earthman, this is the voice
of the Mysterons.
- [Crow] I think it's the voice of Lurch.
- [Mysteron] Your people will pay
for this act of aggression.
Our retaliation will be slow,
but nonetheless effective.
It will be the ultimate destruction
of life on earth.
One of you will be under our control.
You will be instrumental
in avenging the Mysterons.
(dramatic music)
- The attack on your complex was wrong.
We admit it and deeply regret it,
but we on earth want you to know
it was done out of fear
and was not a deliberate act
of aggression against you.
I know you that you can hear this message
and hope that you will answer
so that together we can find a way
of ending this war of nerves between us.
On behalf of the world government
and all people's of the earth,
I offer you the hand of friendship.
I hope that it will be accepted.
(dramatic music)
(upbeat music)
- You know, that's
really pretty good Crow.
- Oh, thank you Joel Hodgson.
- I can see it in every...
Oh, we're on, okay, we're on, hey, Cambot.
This is a thing we're all working on,
me and the puppet bots is a thing you do
where you trace your hand with a crayon,
bring it in, that's good Cambot
and then you put a little beak on it
and little feet
and me and all the robots did it.
Let's see, well, let's
look at yours, Crow.
You see, can you see that.
- [Cambot] Yes, Colonel Jetson.
- [Joel] Bringing in crows there.
- [Cambot] I took the
liberty of adding radar
to my turkey.
- [Joel] See, there's
the radar down there.
And now Cambot, bring
it over to Servo here
and we'll show you Servo's.
- [Servo] As you can
see, it's not very big
so I'd just like to say
that it's very far away.
- That's good, Servo, good job.
- I'm gonna go look for some meat now.
- Okay, some Thanksgiving food, good idea.
- Okay, Gypsy, you ready
to show yours, huh?
- Oh, come on, let's see it.
Ah, come on.
- I bet it's good.
- Come on.
Let us show it, okay, I think.
- No.
- Well, I think it's pretty good.
- Yeah.
- No, it's good I like it.
- I think you did a good job.
There's the head and little feet.
(Gypsy squawking)
- You just made the most beautiful picture
you little monkey.
- Oh, yeah, that's good.
- Oh, we got movie sign,
we better get outta here.
We go through, you go around.
(doors clanking)
- Two hours.
Do you think we will get a reply, Colonel?
- I don't know.
- Well, I wish they'd hurry up.
I can't stand this waiting.
Gentlemen, we are
forgetting we have a guest.
Is there anything I can get you, Doctor?
- Well, Colonel, would it be possible
to see an Angel launch?
- Of course, we'll go up
to the promenade deck.
We'll be able to hear the
Mysteron reply anywhere
on cloud base.
Leftenant Green, arrange
a demonstration launch.
- [Leftenant Green] SIG, Colonel.
- Sig?
- Spectrum is Green.
It means everything is fine.
- SIR, spectrum is red.
Means the opposite.
This way, Doctor.
- Angels One, Two and
Three, prepare for launch.
- There we are, Doctor.
The Angel aircraft are below.
We have five pilots,
code named the Angels.
One is always stationed in
the leading Angel aircraft,
ready for immediate launch.
- [Man] Angel One, immediate launch.
(plane soaring)
- Two more are waiting in
the amber room below deck
on constant alert.
Ready to come up the elevator
into the other aircraft.
- The remaining two are off duty.
They work a round the clock rotor system.
- Here come Angels Two and three now.
(dramatic music)
- [Servo] From La-Z-Boy to
leer jet in three minutes.
- [Man] Immediate launch.
(plane soaring)
- Magnificent.
A truly wonder sight,
but also very practical.
It means we can have our
aircraft fully operational
at 40,000 feet in a matter of seconds.
- Colonel White?
- [Colonel White] What is it, Leftenant?
- Our monitors have picked
up a carrier way, sir.
I believe the Mysterons are about
to answer your transmission.
- Well, gentlemen, the
moment of truth has arrived.
- [Mysteron] This is the
voice of the Mysterons.
Your message has been analyzed
and it has been decided
to allow one member
of spectrum to meet our representative.
If you agree, you must carry out
the following instructions.
Any deviation and the
arrangement will be canceled.
The member of Spectrum
must not carry weapons
or communication equipment of any kind.
He will fly on a course
of one to four magnetic
from cloud base's present position.
Further instructions
will be relayed to you.
This is the voice of the Mysterons.
- [Servo] Hmm, I think
it record on 45, not 33.
- Well, gentlemen, what
are your reactions?
- It's a trap, Colonel.
It means sending an unarmed man
into the jaws of death.
- You're probably right,
but I think we must accept.
We cannot miss this chance.
- I have a code reference for you sir.
The only landfall is
a large desolate volcanic
area in Greenland.
- Greenland, eh?
And ideal spot for a secret rendezvous.
- Colonel, I still say
the risk's too great.
Why should we trust the Mysterons?
- I know the risk, Captain,
but someone must go.
- Sir, if a member of
Spectrum is to be sent,
I am the obvious choice, I'm ready.
- Thank you, Captain Scarlet.
I'll leave immediately.
- [Servo] He likes the laws of death.
- [Crow] It's his show.
(gentle music)
Joel, how come you never
go in the jaws of death?
- [Joel] They wanted
me, but I passed on it.
- [Servo] Completely understandable.
- Captain Scarlet has just passed
the Renvick radar station.
- The last point of contact.
- [Mysteron] Here are your instructions.
Continue on your present course,
then eject in exactly two minutes.
When you land, you will
see a black saloon.
Get into the passenger seat.
- Eject? In the middle of nowhere?
(plane soaring)
- Five, four, three, two, one.
(plane exploding)
- [Servo] Ouch.
Well, at least he won't have to tip.
- [Mysteron] Come in, Captain Scarlet.
You are expected.
- [Crow] It's one of
those theme nightclubs.
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] Hmm, the cloud's on his eye.
- Thank you.
Will I be able to see you?
- [Mysteron] There is no
need for you to see me.
I can hear anything you have to say.
- I have come here unarmed.
Your instructions have
been followed precisely.
- You must listen and
take back this message
to the world.
This is the voice of the Mysterons.
Hear us earthmen and take heed.
You started this war of nerves
with your unprovoked
attack on our complex.
- I came here to negotiate.
- [Mysteron] To take our
revenge against the earth.
You started a shockwave.
- Listen to me.
- [Mysteron] The repercussions
of which will be felt
around the world.
Our retaliation.
- Can you hear me?
- [Mysteron] It will be slow,
but nonetheless effective.
It will mean the ultimate-
- Please listen.
- [Mysteron] Destruction of life on earth.
- That's a recording.
- [Mysteron] Little by little.
(glass breaking)
- [Mysteron] We will bring
the earth to its knees
and finally annihilate it.
- The pulsator.
It's going to explode.
(building exploding)
- A trap. But why, why?
So much energy in one tiny pulsator.
The pulsator, the attack on cloud base.
I must warn them.
- [Crow] Hmm, things a
marionette might say, hmm.
(dramatic music)
- What time is it Leftenant?
- Five minutes to midnight, sir.
(tires squealing)
(dramatic music)
- It's got to work.
- Colonel, I've picked
up some sort of signal.
It's Morse.
- Morse? Let me hear it.
S, c, a, r, l.
It's from Scarlet.
He says the pulsator's
a Mysteron booby trap.
- 30 seconds to midnight, sir.
- Captain Oko, this is an emergency.
Do exactly as I say.
Take the diamond pulsator
to the nearest porthole and jettison it.
- Sig.
- [Colonel White] There will be
an explosive decompression in the room.
Put on a respirator.
- 15 seconds left, sir.
- Hurry Captain Oko.
- Ten.
Nine.
(glass exploding)
Eight.
Seven.
- [Servo] Hmm, nothing
like a good countdown.
- [Leftenant Green] Six.
Five.
- [Servo] That's what I often say.
- [Joe] I know.
- Three.
Two.
One.
(pulsator exploding)
- Firstly, I must thank
you Captain Scarlet
and you Captain Oko.
Because of your initiative,
cloud base is safe.
Well, gentlemen, the events of yesterday
can now be viewed in retrospect.
Our attempt to end the war of nerves
with the Mysterons has failed.
Obviously we were unable to convince them
of our sincerity, but we will try again.
Let us learn from this operation
and steal ourselves for the long road
which lies in front of us.
- [Joel] He's right, you know.
(dramatic music)
(upbeat music)
- [Joel] Jackie Gleason again.
- [Crow] That's the planet Earth, Joel.
- [Joel] Well, what'd you
think of the movie, Crow?
- [Crow] Well, I, uh, I
have some laundry to do.
- [Joel] You have laundry to do.
- [Crow] Now I do if you know what I mean.
- [Joel] What about you, Servo?
- [Servo] Well, it made me laugh,
but most of all, it made me cry.
- [Joel] That's good.
I wish I would have-
- [Servo] It made me think.
- [Joel] Oh, yeah, is that right?
- [Servo] It made me reflect.
- [Joel] I wish we could
have seen the Mysterons.
They never showed them, you know.
- [Servo] That made me think, too.
- [Crow] That's why there were Mysterons
because we never saw them.
- [Joel] I suppose.
- [Servo] That made me wonder.
- [Crow] Ran out of their
special effects budget.
- [Joel] Yeah, they saved on
actors if they could have-
- [Crow] Puppetry coordinator,
puppetry supervision.
- [Joel] That made me mad.
Whoa, lots of character
voices in that one.
- [Servo] Well, time for
me to drain my radiator.
- [Joel] Okay, see you around.
- [Servo] See you up in the front thing.
- [Joel] Okay.
We should get going, too, Crow.
- [Crow] That's right, I
have to get some things done.
- Yeah, go do your puppet laundry.
(upbeat music)
(logo buzzing)
(door banging)
All right, I'm really excited.
I just heard that Gypsy and Servo found
some turkey in the cargo bay.
- Here he comes now.
He said before we eat, we must observe
one Thanksgiving custom of earth.
- Oh, right, to give thanks.
- Make that two Thanksgiving customs,
to give thanks and to
pass the Chex party mix.
- All right, okay.
Thanks.
- Enjoy Joel Hodgson.
- Golly.
- And Crow, you, too.
- Well, never mind.
- Enjoy.
- Hmm, here's some for later.
- Here Crow, I'll give you some.
- I'm out of here.
Did you get some?
- Tasty.
- Oh, here comes Gypsy with
the main course, all right.
Hot turkey and...
Wait a minute, this isn't the kind
of turkey and gravy we have on earth.
- Moo?
- This stuff's in tubes.
- What do you expect on a
communication satellite?
Now, do you want dark meat, white meat
or winter fresh gel.
- Winter fresh gel.
- You're right, you're right, I know.
I should be thankful.
At least I have someone, I mean something
to spend Thanksgiving with.
- Yes.
- What are these crackers.
- Oh, the box said something
like soilant green.
Said it's made from people.
- Oh, they're good, though.
Mine shaped like Edward G. Robinson.
(all laughing)
We'll be right back with a movie.
That's good.